Alvin Garin

Muntinlupa city, Philippines +6399321242045 | garinalvin.e@gmail.com

Experienced professional with over 5 years of experience in the manufacturing industry, with expertise in manufacturing data analysis and probe line support function. Has in-depth knowledge in MS Word, Excel, Powerpoint, basic python programming and SQL. Strong verbal and written communication skills.

Education:

Colegio de Dagupan

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering 2016

Refocus Digital Academy

Data Analytics 2023-Present

Skills:

- SQL
- PostgreSQL
- Basic Python
- Power BI (on-going)
- Advanced Microsoft Excel
- Data Visualization

Professional Work Experiences:

Probe Engineer Allegro Microsystems Philippines

May 2020 – June 2023

Responsibilities:

- Analyzes manufacturing equipment efficiencies.
- Review machine and hardware gage data
- Check and help update process documents.

- Provide line sustaining support
- Update and/or correct process records
- Check possible test program related issues
- Interacts with other group to resolve line issues
- Acts sa secondary supervisor to probe technician
- Generates daily, weekly and monthly reports.
- Performs gathering and analysis of manufacturing data
- Improvement projects
- Perform repairs of Eagle test system and TEL Probers

Key Skills: Microsoft Excel, Power Point, 0+, galaxy/mentor, ETS system programming and hardware debugging, TEL prober operation and maintenance

Probe Technician

October 2017 - April 2020

Responsibilities:

- Performs setup and repairs.
- Troubleshoot Eagle Test Systems
- Troubleshoot Precio octo, P8 and P8xL probers.
- Validates rejects.
- Performed hardware qualifications.
- Performs data gathering
- Trains new technicians

Key Skills: Galaxy/Mentor, ETS and TEL prober hardware repair,